Mark Kelly

Ridgefield, WA 98642 | Phone: 360.721.9342 | Email: kellymark0101@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/MarkKelly00 | Portfolio: https://markkelly.dev/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-kelly-9a1436160/

Full Stack Web Developer & Software Engineer

Spent the last several years building work experience that led me to where I am today: a disciplined worker with strong core values of integrity, excellence, and respect. Technology has been a passion of mine, particularly enjoying the excitement of emerging technologies. Working for the United States Air Force has been a privilege, allowing me to serve my country while growing further in a technical field and as a person giving me the skills to take anywhere. In both my academic and professional life, my professors and peers consistently praised me as proactive, diligent, and oriented. The ability to adapt quickly with teams, technologies, develop highly complex applications, individual projects and excel in solving complex problems, and strong desire to increase efficiencies. Proficient in Spanish.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Node, Python, Express, JSON, jQuery, Redux Database: MySQL, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, Firestore Other: Heroku, Git, Command Line, Agile, Problem Solving, Communication Skills, Bootstrap, Firebase, Microsoft Office Suite

Projects
Alyssandrak.com - Beauty Salon 2020 – 2021
Designed & maintained website for high functionality, easy navigation, and responsiveness. □ Built a full responsive web application. □ Tools used: HTML5, SASS, React, Material-UI.
Alertify- http://alertifynow.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/MarkKelly00/Alertify 2020 - 2020
Interactive web application to alert emergency contact/s via one click.
☐ Built the Alertify as a project with fellow classmates at the University of Oregon.
Alertify works on mobile and standard web browsers to create a list of emergency contacts that you want to Alert in situation, this sends a text of your current location.
□ Tools used: HTML5, Materialize CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, MongoDB, and
Google Maps API
CodeLocker - https://codel0cker.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/MarkKelly00/codeLocker 2020-2020
Full-stack web application that allows developers to save their code in a personalized Locker or
share with the CodeLocker community.
□ Designed an app that all developers to create an account, execute code in embedded
console with option to save for future referencing. This allows the ability to keep code private or
share with others in the CodeLocker community.
☐ Tools used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.JS, Auth0, HTML5, TailwindCSS, and
Javascript

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

2020 - Current

- Developed responsive full stack web applications...
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications with accuracy.
- Maximized applications' efficiency, quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Integrated other APIs for Google Maps, and other services..

UNFI

Ridgefield, WA

Reach Lift Operator/Associate

2011 - 2020

- Restocked/Replenished while taking accountability of all floor merchandise.
- Played a vital role in the transport of merchandise.
- Made sure the product is safely packaged and is placed in an orderly fashion.
- Influenced a positive workplace culture and developed team support of solutions.

United States Air Force

Malmstrom AFB, Montana Missile and Space Systems Technician (2M0X2) 2009-2011

- Serviced, maintained, and supervised actions on missiles, unmanned air vehicles (UAV), boosters, payloads, research and development (R&D) systems, environmental blast doors and valves, associated subsystems, components, and support equipment (SE).
- Operations of launches, tracks, and recovers of UAVs while maintaining related equipment. Performed acquisition and activation activities. Related DoD Occupational Subgroup: 163200.

Key /	Acni	eve	mei	าเร
-------	------	-----	-----	-----

☐ Top Secret Clearance - It's a qualification for my Air Force career received in 2009.
☐ Iraqi Campaign Medal/GWOTEM - After my deployment in Iraq, I was rewarded with
the Iraqi Campaign Medall in Honor of my service along with the Global War on Terrorism
Expedititionary Medal.
 Expert Marksman - While in the Air Force I received a bronze star on my Expert
Marksman ribbon to display that I am a qualified Expert on both the M16 and M9.
 2006-2008 YAA - Received the Youth Achievement Award for community service.

Education

Bootcamp Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Oregon – Eugene, OR

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React, Node.js, Algorithms and Data Structures, MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, Command Line, Agile, Bash, and Git.